The greatest legend of all was real
Alexander is a war, history, action film directed by Oliver Stone.
Alexander, the King of Macedonia, leads his legions
against the giant Persian Empire.
After defeating the Persians, he leads his army across the then known world,
venturing farther than any westerner had ever gone, all the way to India.
Alexander, played by Colin Farrell.
Olympias, played by Angelina Jolie.
Philip, played by Val Kilmer.
Hephaistion, played by Jared Leto.
Cassander, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Old Ptolemy, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Alexander is a 2004 epic historical drama film based on the life of the
ancient Macedonian general and king Alexander the Great.
It was co-written and directed by Oliver Stone and starred Colin Farrell.
The film's original screenplay was derived in part from the book Alexander the Great,
published in 1973 by the University of Oxford historian Robin Lane Fox.
After release, it performed well in Europe, but the American critical reaction was mixed to negative with criticism aimed at
the runtime and historical innacuracies but praise for the performances, action, soundtrack, and visuals.
It grossed $167 million worldwide against a $155 million budget,
thus making it a critical and commercial failure.
Four versions of the film exist: the initial theatrical cut and three home video director's cuts: the
"Director's Cut" in 2005, the "Final Cut" in 2007, and the "Ultimate Cut" in 2014.
The two earlier DVD versions of Alexander ("director's cut" version and the
theatrical version) sold over 3.5 million copies in the United States.
Oliver Stone's third version, Alexander Revisited: The Final Cut (2007), sold nearly a million copies
and became one of the highest-selling catalog items from Warner Bros (as of 2012).
The film explores themes of egypt, elephant, aristotle, persia, greece.
The tone is emotional.